Attention , ladies and gentlemen ...
Due to an accident on the line we 've stopped the train .
As you see , we 're only halfway into the station .
The doors will now be opened so you can get out .
Please do as you 're told .
Okay , let 's see .
Now walk through 2 carriages , to the platform .
What 's happened ?
A man 's thrown himself in front of the train .
When you reach the platform , leave as soon as you can .
Don 't look at the track . The man 's been cut in two .
Come on , hurry up .
Move . Come on .
THESIS
Out you come .
Just one line , please .
Let 's go . Come on . Eyes off the track .
There 's nothing to see . Get off . That way .
A man threw himself on the track .
Right , that way . No looking .
Don 't look .
Don 't touch anything
Sorry for the inconvenience . Thank you .
Please , get off . Nothing worth seeing .
Move on . Don 't be so morbid .
Let me through .
Come on , off you go . Keep moving .
Move along , that 's enough .
SCHOOL OF MASS COMMUNICATIONS . NOVEMBER 1995 .
- It 's just the outline . - True , but I like the approach .
It 's a delicate subject .
It 's a God-send for the morbid .
But you 're being objective .
Thanks .
Okay .
See you in class .
Just one more thing ...
on section 7 ...
" Audiovisual violence . "
I 'm looking for information .
What kind of information ?
Images . Images never seen on TV , because they 're too violent .
You have access to the archives .
Maybe you could get me something interesting .
Does that seem interesting to you ?
Not personally . But it 'll be useful for my project .
- Violent images ... - As violent as possible .
It 'll be awkward asking for films like that .
They 'll think I 'm warped .
I can 't promise anything .
- Come see me tomorrow . - Thanks .
Until next week , and please go to the cinema .
Hi .
You 're Chema ?
I 'm Angela .
Great .
Can I ask you a favor ?
I hear you like violent films , and you 've got quite a collection .
Of what ?
You know , gore , porn ...
That 's not true . I wouldn 't give them to you anyway .
If you want to get turned on , go to a sex-shop .
It 's for my thesis , on audiovisual violence .
You should 've done it on Mickey Mouse .
You want to see those tapes ?
So you have them .
Yes or no ?
You University lot like to show off what you 're doing .
But you haven 't got a clue about the cinema .
What is cinema for you ?
What I 've got in here .
Hypocrites say my films are shit ,
but they 're dying to see them .
It 's for my thesis . I have no interest in your fi ...
Hey !
Come on in .
Do you want something ?
No , thanks .
No beating about the bush , right ?
Don 't say I didn 't tell you .
Do you live with thieves ?
I live alone .
- And your parents ? - They don 't live in Madrid .
This belonged to my grandmother . She snuffed it last year .
Don 't touch anything .
Nobody 's ever come to my hideaway . Feel lucky .
Why give me the honor ?
You 're gorgeous .
- Thanks . - You were born that way .
Sit down . It 's free .
Now , what do you want to see ?
What have you got ?
All types of porn ...
soft , hard , oriental , you name it .
This one 's shit hot .
Porn doesn 't really interest me .
It 's easy to get . If that 's all you 've got ...
So you want action , eh ? Alright then .
I need violent images .
Violent images . How nice . You 'll shit yourself .
What film then ?
" Fresh blood " . Avery beautiful and educational film .
What are they doing ?
What do you think ? Taking out his brain .
Oh my God !
That 's what you wanted . Don 't get squeamish now .
Everything you see is real .
Executions , beatings , hangings ...
Great stuff !
- Good afternoon . - Good afternoon , Mr. Figueroa .
I 'd like to ask a favor . I 'm after a Czechoslovakian film .
I can 't remember its name . Can I see the titles ?
- Do you want to go in the storeroom ? - It 's not the norm , but ...
Come with me .
It 's strange .
No one ever asks to go in ,
- but you 're the second today . - Is that so ?
Another professor came a moment ago . He comes here often .
Professor !
He can 't hear me .
Here you are . According to category . I 'll leave you to it .
Shouldn 't we wait for him to finish ?
I don 't think that 'll bother him .
- Does it bother you ? - Of course not .
It 's very big .
You won 't bump into each other .
See you .
Hello !
PORNOGRAPHY AND OTHER GENRES : SHELF 54 .
How horrible !
Do people really watch these movies ?
You , for instance .
That 's different . I don 't enjoy them .
It 's disgusting .
Have you ever seen anyone killed ?
What do you think ?
Not TV stuff , but the real thing .
This is real . What more do you want ?
You don 't get me .
I 've never seen anyone killed .
Mr. Figueroa . We 've got to close now .
Hello !
That 's it .
- Hi ! - Hello , bookworm .
- Have you seen Figueroa ? - You like older men , eh ?
Professor ?
Did you find him ?
No .
He didn 't come to class .
Nor did you . Where were you ?
Never mind . I 'm off .
Do you think a film
can kill someone ?
A heart attack , or something like that , caused by what they see .
What 's got into you ? Wasn 't yesterday enough ?
You 're a real sadist .
So you 'd probably fuck even me .
I 've got money .
- We 're off . Sena ! - Coming .
- Sure you don 't want to come ? - I 've got to work on my thesis .
Then you 'll ask for my clothes .
Come on . Let 's go .
Don 't work too hard .
- Mummy ! - What ?
- What 's on this tape ? - What tape ?
In the video . Did you watch it last night ?
No . Rewind it and take a look .
- Hey ! - This tape 's mine .
- Can 't I watch it ? - It 's for my thesis . Boring stuff .
How do you know ?
No .
I 'm sure it 's not a report .
Silence .
Be quiet . Quiet .
Hello , everybody .
I suppose you 've heard the news .
Professor Figueroa died on Tuesday .
He was found in one of the screening rooms .
Apparently he had an asthma attack while watching a film .
I bet it was Spanish .
Have you seen the film ?
No .
You probably took it .
My name 's Castro .
Jorge Castro .
I 'm a professor of Audiovisual Psychology .
Some of you probably know me .
I 'm going to replace Professor Figueroa for now .
I know the program .
So there shouldn 't be any problem to carry on as normal .
Which reminds me ...
Where is it ?
I believe Prof. Figueroa was directing your thesis .
I 'd be glad to carry on .
We can talk when you like .
- You 're losing it . - I 'm not .
You found him dead and took the tape .
- I did not ! - It 's her ! She took the tape !
- Why should I give it to you ? - ' Cause I showed you mine .
- Why do you want it ? - Why do you ?
- For my thesis . - Bullshit ! What the fuck 's on it ?
I don 't know .
What ?
I haven 't seen it yet .
You 're stupid .
Your place or mine ?
Give me the tape .
Now the fun begins .
I can 't .
Too bad for you .
- Fuckin ' hell ! - Switch it off !
It 's real .
What ?
A girl , tied to a chair , being beaten by a guy wearing a balaclava .
Why are you doing this to me ?
Fuck , it 's awful .
I can 't .
What 's he going to do to her ?
- Don 't watch . - I don 't want to . Don 't look !
Don 't look !
I know that girl .
She was at the University .
She disappeared 2 years ago .
Is she dead ?
What a question . They blew her brains out .
What 's he doing to her now ?
- Cutting her up . - Jesus Christ ! Switch it off !
I told you so . That bastard 's a butcher .
I think her name was Vanessa .
Why did they do that to her ?
That looks like a garage , doesn 't it ?
Why ?
It 's a garage .
- It 's a garage . - So ?
- She was tortured , then killed . - You don 't say .
How can you watch that crap ?
- You stole that crap . - I didn 't know what it was .
You could 've imagined . Deep down you love it .
- What are you saying ? - Just what you 've heard .
That 's nonsense .
- Hang on . What the fuck 's this ? - I refuse to look .
I 'm talking about the texture .
Look at the horizontal lines .
I only see intestines .
You 've learnt nothing in 5 years . The texture 's different .
- So ? - It 's a digital zoom .
The idiot 's used a digital zoom .
So what ?
We can find out what camera he used .
Really ? How many cameras have digital zooms ?
100 ? 5,000 ? 10,000 ?
How many cameras had digital zooms 2 years ago ?
Not many . Very few .
Autofocus , light control , shake control ,
Stereo mic ... Shit .
Here . Digital zoom . The center of the image will get ...
That 's the B-2000 . It came out this year .
Let 's see .
Stroboscopic effect , solar effects ...
I 'm sure there was one .
The XT-500 ?
- Fuck , that 's it . The XT-500 . - Which one ?
Here it is . I 'm sure ...
Autofocus , audio dubbing ... Digital zoom !
" This allows significant
enlargements of the original . "
See ? He did use an XT-500 .
It 's the HI 8 system , I think .
Fascinating ,
but I 'm going home for dinner .
Are you hungry ?
No , afraid .
Don 't take it with you .
I want to see it again .
Her parents have heard nothing about her since .
Sena . Come here .
Have you been snooping around in my room ?
Why ? Of course not .
I can 't stand people sifting through my things .
- It wasn 't me . - I know my room .
Someone 's been nosing around .
Not me .
You were after that tape , weren 't you ?
Leave me alone .
- Hello . - It 's Chema . I 've got something .
I 'm not interested . That 's it . Okay ?
- Someone 's been in my room . - What ?
Calm down , will you .
- No one knows us . Don 't be afraid . - Of course not .
You should check your room as well .
No one 's been here .
I 've got something you must see .
- I can 't . - Yes you can .
- I don 't want to . - Yes you do .
At first , I thought nothing of it .
Please ! Don 't ! Please !
Please . Please .
Look !
- What ? - It 's been cut .
Look again .
No , please !
Please !
Why are you doing this to me ?
He 's cut off a bit .
Not only here . The film 's full of cuts .
All in the same way .
Look . It 's very slight .
He 's almost in the same position .
Why cut there ?
In a film like this , you 've got to see everything .
The more you see , the better .
So why cut it ?
So we don 't see something .
Please , why me ?
Please ! No !
She was about to say something .
What ?
Something he doesn 't want us to hear .
- His name . - His name .
She knew who he was .
- She knew him . - So what ?
That changes things . We now know more about him .
Listen ...
You sound like the police .
Don 't insult me .
We 've got to know who
- Vanessa 's friends were . - Are you crazy ?
This guy might be one of them .
Look ...
I 've had enough of this .
You 're scared shitless .
Of course . This is no game . These people really kill .
Piss off , then . I 'll do it on my own .
You don 't understand . I said it 's over .
For you as well .
I don 't want any problems .
What do you mean ? I won 't get you into trouble .
So what now ?
Go after anyone with a camera like that ?
What if you find him ? Or he finds you ?
Then it 's my problem .
Too right .
I 've never been here , I don 't know you .
I 've never seen that tape .
What is the cinema ?
Don 't fool yourselves . The cinema is an industry .
It 's about money . Millions invested in films ...
and then made at the box office .
Our country has no cinema because there 's no concept of industry .
No communication between the makers and their audience .
We 've reached a very critical stage ; our cinema won 't be saved
unless it is understood as an industrial phenomenon .
As students of cinema ,
you are the future of Spanish cinema .
Save it .
The American industry 's out there
trampling on you ,
and there 's only one way to compete :
give the public what it wants .
Don 't forget that .
Thank you .
- Angela . - Hi .
- How are you ? - Fine .
- A drink ? - No , thanks .
Here 's my work , sir ...
Please don 't be so formal . I 'm not that old .
I haven 't done much recently .
It doesn 't matter . I just want to get an idea .
Anything you want to tell me ?
No .
Fine .
UNIVERSITY STUDENT DISAPPEARS .
WHERE 'S OUR DAUGHTER ?
COURT BLOCKS NEW INQUIRY IN ROMERO CASE .
... the rest of the staff
will be taken on for the rest of the project .
And that 's all for today .
See you tomorrow .
Don 't forget to bring me your work .
- What do you want ? - What do you want ?
This is yours .
You 're studying journalism ?
- No , cinema and TV . - One of us .
Give them to me , please .
Are you doing some project ?
No , well , yes , a project .
- You 're in luck . - Why ?
I knew her .
She was a friend of my girlfriend . I know what happened .
That 's alright , thanks .
I 've got all I need .
There are things you don 't know .
Where were you ?
Yolanda , this is ...
- Hi . - Hi .
Bye .
She 's doing a report on Vanessa .
Can I have a word with you ?
Hi , Roadrunner .
Is it true about the project , or are you pulling my leg ?
No , it 's true .
And the camera ?
Camera ?
For the project .
Of course !
- The truth is ... - You 're confused .
What ?
No , I mean , we still haven 't got it .
- We 've got to get permission . - Will this do ?
I 've had enough !
I 've had enough ! Bullshit !
Chema , you 've got to help me .
- Imagine interviewing him ? - He pressurized me .
Pressurized you ?
What the fuck can one ask a murderer ?
- Was Vanessa normal ? - I 'm glad you ask ,
because she was wonderful , full of life ,
until I killed her , of course .
- Did she mix with strange people ? - No , she was an angel .
Did she seem strange prior to her disappearance ?
What do I know ?
- Do you think she was killed ? - You can 't ask that .
- It 's fundamental . - You 'll fuck up if you ask that .
If I don 't , he might think I 'm avoiding the issue .
Stop thinking about what he might think .
This isn 't your thesis .
- What 's the matter ? - I 'm leaving .
- Why ? - Because .
Great .
I 'm sorry .
Where are my keys ?
You still haven 't told me his name .
Where are they ?
- These ? - They 're my sister 's .
- I never lose my keys . - Welcome to the club .
This is Bosco . Bosco , Chema .
Hi .
- How 's it going ? - Is this the camera ?
Chema 'll operate the camera .
You know how it works , don 't you ?
I think so .
When you 're ready .
Bosco was in class with Vanessa .
Tell us what happened .
She didn 't come to class for a few days .
We called her house . They said she 'd disappeared .
The police looked for her for months
but we never heard anymore about her .
Do you think she was kidnapped ?
Some people think so , but that 's absurd .
After she disappeared , she wrote home ...
saying she 'd fallen in love , that she 'd run off with this guy .
No ransom money was ever demanded .
And didn 't you suspect anything ?
Didn 't you know anything about her private life ?
I don 't spy on anyone .
Do you ?
Do you know who she might have run off with ?
No , but knowing her , it had to be someone
very special .
In what way ?
In every way .
Vanessa ...
two years have gone by and
I 'm sure you 've made a new life .
But wherever you are
your friends won 't forget you .
Please , Vanessa ,
Come back . I love you .
- He was crying . - Bullshit .
- Suppose it 's true . - Don 't go along with his game .
He looks at you with his angel face and you believe every word he says .
What ? Do you like him ?
- Don 't be silly . - Don 't you be silly .
What about the letter ?
It shows that Vanessa fell in love with a bloke .
- Who ? - Who do you think ?
How can you be so sure ? Besides , Bosco 's got a girlfriend .
Get this into your head .
Apart from being a stuck-up little shit ,
is a psychopath .
And that 's it .
Can 't you see how he looks at you ?
He 's dying to blow your brains out while he fucks you up the ass .
- He 's nuts . - Sounds like you know him .
Very well . Encourage him , you 'll see .
He 'll come round , with knife and camera .
- So what now ? - Nothing .
Nothing ?
We know who it is . So just go home .
- We 've got to tell the police . - Like hell !
Not me . Anyway , we 've got no proof .
We don 't even know where the old man got the tape .
From the archives .
No way .
Hello !
Anyone home ?
Angela ?
Hello , darling .
A friend of yours is here . He 's gorgeous .
Is Angela in ?
There she is . Make yourself at home .
Thanks .
Are you a bit nervous ?
How did you get my address ?
I do my investigating too .
I see . What do you want ?
I 've brought the interview .
Thank you .
There was no need to .
That 's not why I 'm here .
Why then ?
For shots of you .
What ?
There are no takes of you doing the interview .
We need them for the editing .
Of course , I forgot .
When you 're ready .
What , here ?
Yeah , it 's closed . You can 't tell where we are .
You 'll see .
Where 's your bedroom ?
I don 't like to be taped .
Don 't give me that .
You 're so pretty .
Don 't worry , it won 't take long .
How long have you had that camera ?
About 4 months .
It 's no longer on the market .
Good God ! You know everything .
I got it second hand .
Why do you ask ?
No special reason .
You like asking questions , don 't you ?
Can I ask you one ?
Sure .
What 's the color of my eyes ?
I don 't know .
I haven 't really looked .
So you 're a liar as well .
Much longer ?
You in a hurry ?
It 's almost lunchtime .
Bosco , stay for lunch , will you ?
- I 'd love to . - Great .
I 'll nip out and get a few things . Be good now .
What are you doing ?
The light 's bad for this camera .
- Sit on the bed . - Why ?
I haven 't got a good focus from here .
Sit on the bed .
That 's it .
When you 're ready .
We 're now talking with Bosco ,
a classmate of Vanessa 's , who was close to her prior to her ...
You 're not checking ?
It 's one straight take .
Look at me as you ask the questions .
Did Vanessa mix with strange people ? Do you think she was kidnapped ?
Did you know about her private life ? Who could she have run away with ?
That 's it .
Hang on .
Your approving nod , as you hear my answers .
You can put them in after .
- One thing ... - What ?
- Yesterday , we were closer . - I don 't think so .
Does it bother you if I come closer ?
No .
When will it begin to bother you ?
Please .
Every word means an inch closer .
It 's not funny .
Don 't speak .
Are you nervous ?
- Of course not . - Not a word .
The mouth can be a big killer .
I 'm not going to die .
I 'm-not-going-to-die .
Five inches .
What 's the color of my eyes ?
Are you going to kill me ?
Six inches closer for saying that .
One more word
and we 'll collide .
I thought you liked this .
Next time I 'll punch you on the nose .
There won 't be a next time .
Angela , how can you let Bosco set the table ?
- Who changed the channel ? - I did . The news is a bore .
What would you know ? Where 's the remote control ?
Bosco , so you work as well as study ?
I film every now and then .
On ?
Anything ... A wedding .
- A baptism . - Does it pay ?
A fair bit .
Angela 's never done anything like that .
She 's got enough with her thesis .
Are you doing a thesis ?
I 've just started .
On what ?
I 'm not sure yet .
" Audiovisual violence and the family " .
Does violence interest you ?
Not really .
She loves it .
Something 's wrong with her brain .
She spends the day analyzing violent films .
- Sena , shut up . - Is the project part of your thesis ?
No . Why ?
The last film she brought home was something .
Are you doing a project ? On what ?
Shall we eat ? That 's enough talk .
What do you study ?
- I started Law this year . - Law ?
Well , well .
I wanted to study Law .
Is that so ? Why didn 't you ?
I don 't know . I 'm not cut out for it .
You 've got to be very ...
determined .
And intelligent .
I 'm not , and I 'm studying it .
Bosco , your meat 's getting cold .
You look it .
What ?
Intelligent .
How 's Yolanda ?
Who 's Yolanda ?
The girl he 's dating .
We 've broken up .
Really ?
More or less . This meat 's very good .
He 's been to your house ?
Fuck me !
Why did you let him in ?
It 's not my fault if he wins my family over .
It 's you he 's won over .
Not even coffee for me , and you take him home .
Stop being silly and listen .
He says he bought the camera second hand , 4 months ago .
Second hand ? That snobby git ?
Sure it was new , with a guarantee . He 's tricked you again .
- We can check . - Check what ?
You either believe him , or me .
Don 't talk rubbish .
- Good morning . - Good morning .
I 've got a problem . I 've lost a bill .
They lost it at the shop too . They told me ...
- I could get it here . - What was it ?
An XT-500 camera .
That must have been bought ...
Two years ago .
The guarantee 's expired .
I know . But I like to keep bills .
That 's good .
Let 's see .
1993 ...
- Are you from Madrid ? - Yes .
Your name .
I bought it in my brother 's name , Bosco Herranz .
He has to come himself .
On the phone they told me that wasn 't necessary .
Who told you that ?
A girl , I think .
One moment .
SCHOOL
OF MASS COMMUNICATIONS
Fuckin ' hell !
Fuck !
I knew it .
Freddy Kruger himself .
Long time no see .
I 've been busy .
- Jerking yourself off . - Less than you .
Can I look at the closed circuit recordings ?
Do you want me to get fired ?
- The 12th , in the archives . - Not so fast .
What 's in it for me ?
- My body . - No shit .
High class porn .
Hello .
How did you get in ?
What do you want ?
Don 't you know ?
To kill you .
Angela . Phone .
Some guy Castro .
- Hello ? - Hello , Angela .
- Hello . - Hope I didn 't get you up .
Not at all .
I 've looked at your work . I wanted to talk about it .
Angela ?
Yes .
How about today at 11 , in my office ?
- Fine . - Great .
- See you later . - Bye .
- Hello ? - Is Angela there ?
No , she isn 't .
Yes .
- Hi . - Hi , Angela .
Come in .
- How are you ? - Fine .
- Have a seat . - Thank you .
Cigarette ?
No thanks , I don 't smoke .
Let 's see now .
It 's somewhere here .
I 'm hopeless .
Here it is .
Let 's see .
Why does violence interest you ?
Because we come across it daily in the cinema , on TV ,
and we 're now too used to it .
- So ? - That worries me .
Why ?
Because I don 't like violence .
Do you reject it ?
Of course .
Always ?
Yes .
Violence is also something innate to us all .
We can 't sensor every film .
But the director must realise what he 's doing .
The director 's only got to do what the public wants .
It 's the basic principle of any show .
Do you reject show business ?
No , but ...
It 's a very complex issue .
For example ...
What type of violence do you want
to focus on ?
What ?
Any genre in particular ?
I get the impression , correct me if I 'm wrong ...
I think your approach is rather ...
- Superficial ? - Yes .
You can 't be .
This is a research project .
These are just notes .
So you 're investigating ?
What ?
I don 't know . You tell me .
Tell you what ?
What you 're investigating .
I didn 't say that , you did .
Okay , then .
Since you don 't seem willing to cooperate ...
I don 't get it .
Okay , I 'll tell you in a different way .
What killed Figueroa ?
Why do you ask me that ?
He was your director of research . You must know what killed him .
You said it was an asthma attack .
He was quite old .
But I wonder what he saw in that room
that could 've killed him .
Any idea ?
No .
You love to theorize . You must have some theory
- about it . - I don 't .
Angela ?
I think you 're very intelligent .
You 'll go very far .
That 's why I don 't understand your behavior .
I don 't understand you .
Really ?
You don 't understand me ?
I think you do .
Think what you wish . I 've heard enough .
You know something ?
So have I.
I hate these situations .
It 's humiliating to be caught lying .
Don 't you think so ?
You wonder why people lie ?
Why are you lying ?
What 's on that tape ?
You 've lost your voice .
Very well then .
I want that tape in my office , tomorrow .
Okay ?
Now , tell me . Why did you take it ?
- Hello ? - Is Angela there ?
No . Who is it ?
Where is she ?
She had a meeting with a professor at the University .
Who ?
Angela , I can 't direct the thesis of someone who steals ,
lies , and , worst of all ,
who doesn 't trust me .
For the last time . Why did you take it ?
I don 't know .
- Where did you get it ? - I don 't know .
- Was it yours ? - No !
- You wanted to get it back ? - No .
- So why did you take it ? - I don 't know .
I 'm getting tired of this .
No professor will direct your thesis
if you 're not straight with them .
It 's nothing to do with my thesis .
It 's more serious .
I 'm all ears .
No one knows this .
Hello ?
What ?
For you .
Me ?
Take it in there .
- Hello . - Angela . It 's Chema .
Get out of there right now !
What the hell are you doing there ? That guy 's in it !
- How do you know that ? - Does he know about the tape ?
- He knows I took it . - The bastard knows everything .
He wants it back .
Find some excuse and get out of there .
Hello ?
Okay .
I think I 've got to go .
- Really ? - Yes .
See you .
Shouldn 't we finish ?
Angela !
Listen , please ...
- My thesis , my degree ... - Your life 's at stake .
- I called you all day yesterday . - I called you too .
- He 'll come after me now . - He 's one of them .
- I thought it was only Bosco . - You 're wrong .
How many are there ?
Not a clue . But Castro 's one of them .
- How do you know that ? - Shit !
He knew you 'd taken the tape .
Of course . A closed circuit camera recorded me .
Yes , and another camera recorded him .
- That 's Figueroa . - Hang on .
- Where was he ? - In that corner .
He found out everything . He found the tape .
- What 's in that corner ? - An underground store-room .
- Where they hide things . - What things ?
I 've taken some .
Vanessa 's not the only one . There were other victims .
It 's not an isolated incident . It 's a business :
Accidents , torture , killings .
It 's all down there .
- The cameras must be there . - What cameras ?
13 XT-500 cameras , bought by the University 2 years ago .
Do you know what that means ?
First of all that Bosco 's probably got nothing to do with this .
Not again . Why do you always
- defend him ? - There are more cameras .
Any student could 've made that film .
No student made that film . I 'm sure .
- How do you know that ? - Because I did ...
projects with those cameras .
What ?
2 years ago . Before they were removed .
Why didn 't you tell me ?
I 'm telling you now .
Those projects have nothing to do with this .
Those cameras are probably gathering dust somewhere .
They 've disappeared . No one knows where they are .
Great .
- They 've got to be down there . - There 're only tapes .
We 've got to find them .
I 've been down there . There 're only tapes .
- Tonight , Chema . - No way !
Listen to me , just this once .
You 're doing this for him .
You 've fallen for that bastard , you idiot .
Tonight , idiot .
What do you want ?
To talk with you .
About ?
Vanessa was killed .
With so much theory , we weren 't going anywhere .
So Vanessa and I went to a director 's workshop .
Bosco too .
We did a couple of things with the cameras .
- What type of cameras ? - I can 't remember .
A guy in another class took it very seriously .
He was always telling us what to do .
Bosco and that guy went for it .
They started working together .
One day they asked a girl to act in a short .
She had to take her clothes off ,
and , well , I left halfway through .
Why ?
It was awful .
And the professor didn 't say anything ?
- Who was the professor ? - Jorge Castro .
Do you know him ?
The worst was still to come .
Towards the end of the year ,
Bosco 's friend told us about snuff .
Do you know what that is ?
They would choose someone , anyone ,
kidnap , torture and kill them , and record everything .
No editing effects , no make-up .
Everything in one sequence shot .
He was obsessed with snuff .
Vanessa and I started to get scared because
he said it was very easy to make films like that .
I told Bosco we should get out .
And ?
They stopped talking to each other . I don 't know why .
The workshop closed .
A week later , Vanessa disappeared .
They said she ran away from home .
She 'd have told me .
I 'm sure . That guy killed her .
He used her to make a snuff movie .
What about the letter ?
They sent it after she disappeared .
She might have been forced to write it .
And the guy ?
Your friend , with glasses .
I 've seen you with him .
There are more . Do you watch TV ?
They 're cases like Vanessa 's .
5 girls in 2 years .
" The police suspect the existence of a video snuff network " .
There 's no clear motive .
No bodies .
Have you told Bosco ?
We haven 't spoken much lately .
Besides , he wouldn 't believe me .
Chema 'd never do that .
You never know .
- I know him . - Me too .
And I know it 's him .
- You don 't believe me ? - Exactly .
And this ?
You don 't believe it either ?
" The best woman in the world found her other half .
She wore the trousers , he gave the blows .
You had many lovers , none of them alive today .
They died , crushed , while making love .
There are times
when the truth ... "
We can go now .
Did you know Bosco ?
Did you ? Did you ?
- Yes . - Great .
Thanks for telling me , now .
You told him about snuff .
So ? Making snuff movies is something else .
Why do you want to find Vanessa 's friends
when you know who they are ?
I hardly knew Vanessa , and her crazy friend even less .
I only knew Bosco .
Why did you fall out ?
- I didn 't trust him . - You didn 't trust him .
He looks nice and sweet , but he 's a right bastard .
You 're the bastard . You 've been lying to me .
You said the project had nothing to do with this .
I didn 't want to be associated with Bosco .
I didn 't want to frighten you .
I didn 't want you to think that I ...
Since when do you care what I think of you ?
You 're right . Think what you want .
- And suppose I think that ... - What ?
Nothing . Forget it .
- What about the cameras ? - I know the security guy .
Hi .
Now what ?
It was around here .
This way .
These tunnels lead to the old heaters .
No one 's been down here in years .
This way .
See ? Only tapes .
Figueroa took the first one .
How many are there ?
About 200 .
Must be good business .
What are you doing ?
Help me find the cameras .
Bloody hell !
Shit !
- What is it ? - The masters .
- Worth a fortune . - Are they the originals ?
No , but they 've got to be here .
- Chema , don 't waste time . - Everything 's in the originals .
- If we find them , they 're fucked . - They must have destroyed them .
What was that ?
It 's been closed from outside .
No way !
Or perhaps worse .
Worse ?
Shit . We 've been locked in . Be quiet .
- Chema , where are you ? - Beside you . You 're suffocating me .
- What are they going to do to us ? - Goodness knows .
- Do you smoke ? - No .
- Shit , we need a lighter . - I 've got matches .
- Seriously ? - I think so .
Why are you breathing like that ?
Like a dog .
Fuck .
Give me the matches .
It 's half empty . Good .
We 've got to keep moving . We can 't let them find us .
There . There 's someone . Looking at us .
- It 's our shadow . - No . No .
You disappoint me .
- I 'm scared . - Fuckin ' hell ! Me too .
But that won 't get us out of here .
- What 's happened ? - The match has gone out .
Chema , hold me .
- What 's happened ? - Someone 's touched me .
You told me to hold you !
Don 't leave me .
Why have you gone quiet ?
- Why aren 't you saying anything ? - What can I say ?
I don 't know . Tell me who you are .
What you do .
I 'm Chema , I 'm walking .
I 'm walking , I 'm Chema .
Hello , I 'm Chema .
The blood 's no longer flowing in my arm .
Sorry .
I 'll tell you a story ,
for children .
Once upon a time , there was a princess who lived in a big palace .
And ?
Let 's see . This way .
When she was 13 they had a big party for her ,
with clowns , magicians , acrobats .
But this bored her .
Then an ugly dwarf appeared , jumping around ,
doing pirouettes .
" Please , keep on jumping , " said the princess .
But the dwarf couldn 't .
So the princess was sad and went to her chamber .
The dwarf soon went to get her ,
sure she would go to live with him in the wood .
" She 's not happy here , " he thought .
" I 'll take care of her . I 'll always make her laugh . "
The dwarf searched the palace for the princess ' room ,
but he saw something awful in one of the rooms .
A monster with bloody , deformed eyes ,
huge feet and hairy hands .
The dwarf almost died when he realized that he was
looking at himself in a mirror .
Just then , the princess walked in with her cortege .
" There you are . How nice ! Dance for me again , please . "
But the dwarf was on the ground , unable to move .
The Court doctor took his pulse .
" He won 't dance for you again , princess , " he said .
" Why ? "
" Because his heart is broken . "
And the princess said :
" From now on ,
anyone who sets foot in this palace must not have a heart . "
The wire bends and the match ends .
We 'll never know which way to go .
There must be another exit .
So what ? We can 't see anything .
Chema , strike a match here .
What is it ?
Shit !
- What are you doing ? - Burn it .
Go on .
Fuck !
- This is the editing room . - Jesus !
Look . I told you so .
They 've thrown away what they no longer need .
But Bosco 's camera might be one of these .
I 'm cold .
Do you want my coat ?
No thank you .
Good .
How many matches are left ?
Fuck !
What now ?
I don 't know .
It 's burning out . Take some more clothes off .
- Why don 't you ? - Okay , it was a daft idea .
Are they going to come and kill us ?
Yes .
What are we going to do ?
Shit . It 's going out .
Never mind .
I can 't see your face .
I wouldn 't know if it was someone else .
Five ,
four , three , two ...
- It 's not funny . - One .
Good-bye , princess .
I 'm freezing .
Hug me if you want to .
I want to .
Go on , then .
Chema ?
Don 't look at the track .
What 's the color of my eyes ?
You 've fallen in love with that bastard , you idiot .
What killed Figueroa ?
Because his heart 's broken .
The police know everything .
You 've lied to me before .
You killed Vanessa . You killed all of them .
I 've never killed anyone .
I only edit the films .
- Have you seen them ? - They 're rubbish .
You 've got to give the public what it wants .
This is just the beginning .
Who killed them then ?
I 'll tell you his name if you tell me who called you this morning .
You know very well what 's going to happen now .
That person won 't come .
I don 't know where he is .
You 're lucky ,
I won 't make you suffer .
It 'll be painless .
Now , please ,
for your own good ,
don 't move your head .
His name is Jorge Castro .
He 's pointing a gun at me now .
Very well then ,
don 't move .
My name is Angela .
I 'm going to be killed .
- Exactly ... - No !
He 's dead .
Didn 't you want to see a killing ?
Didn 't you ?
Chema !
I 've found a way out .
I didn 't pull the trigger . He did .
I didn 't kill him .
What are we going to do now ?
What are we going to do ?
To begin with , shut your gob .
We mustn 't see each other for a while .
I 'll keep the master copies .
And let that fucker come for them if he 's got the balls .
Suppose it 's not him .
The Third Man .
- Citizen Kane . - No , The Third Man .
Told you so .
Hi .
- Something wrong ? - No .
I 'm going to bed .
I thought you were with Sena . She 's with your friend .
What friend ?
Bosco . He called a short while ago . They went to a party .
Did they say where ?
- What are you doing here ? - Where is he ?
In the bath . Do you want a drink ?
- No . Let 's go ba ... - He 's left his girl . He likes me .
Let 's go home .
Why ?
Sena , just go .
- Why ? - Bosco and I are together .
You 're the gooseberry here .
Am I supposed to believe that ?
I 'm going to the toilet .
That way .
What 's going on ?
- Don 't do anything to me . - What can I possibly do to you ?
What do you want from me ?
Leave my sister alone .
- It 's you I love . - What for ?
I told you not to come .
Let 's go to the police .
Yeah , right now .
I 'm serious .
That 's enough !
- Get out of the way . - You 're worse than a child .
I don 't want to go to prison .
You 're not going to . It was in self-defense .
- Who 's going to believe that ? - It 's on film .
So ?
- We know about the cameras . - So ?
Cops don 't like me .
Nobody likes me .
Last night ...
Chema , it 's too much for me now .
Is that so ?
Let 's go to the police , or I 'll go mad .
Where are you going ?
To have a shower .
We 've got to look presentable .
Chema ...
I won 't leave you .
Nor me you .
- Chema , where are the masters ? - I can 't hear you .
Hello ? Police .
Why did you lock up from inside ?
- What 's going on ? - What 's the matter ?
Someone 's been calling all afternoon .
- Who ? - I don 't know .
They took me for you .
What did they say ?
Called me a whore , and threatened to kill me .
It 's him .
Angela .
It was a girl .
Bosco , I know you 're there .
You can 't fool me anymore .
No more lies .
They saw you at a disco last night .
How could you ?
She doesn 't love you .
She 's a lying bitch . They all are .
Who 's going to love you like me ?
Bosco , you can 't leave me like this .
You can 't . I won 't allow it .
I 'm capable of anything ...
Do you hear me ?
Don 't answer the phone . Let no one in .
Where are you going ?
I won 't be long .
- What are you doing here ? - Can I come in ?
I called your house . They gave me this address .
I come here at weekends .
Come in .
Are you alone ?
Yes , my parents only come in summer .
- Sorry to bother you . - Don 't worry ,
I was trying to study ...
I 'm glad you 've come .
- Yolanda knows about last night . - I know .
I want you to talk to her .
What for ?
We 've broken up .
She 's been calling my home .
Take no notice .
She threatened to kill me .
You 're not the first .
What do you mean ?
She couldn 't stand me talking with other girls .
It was too much .
She threatened all of them .
Vanessa too ?
What ?
She knew about you and Vanessa , didn 't she ?
What are you saying ?
There was nothing between me and Vanessa .
You 're always up to something , aren 't you ?
Yolanda 's right .
You 're something else .
I 'm beginning to think so too .
Poor Angela ,
always worried .
So I should .
Why ?
What 's the matter ?
I don 't want to carry on with this .
Why are you playing with me ?
I 've got to go .
- Last night you were different . - I was drunk .
Liar .
Are you ever going to tell me ?
- What ? - That you like me .
I like you .
Let 's do it then .
There 's light outside .
The fuse must have blown .
I 'll have a look .
Bosco ?
I 've come to save you again .
Don 't !
Have no fear . Give that to me .
Angela !
Tell me what you see .
You wanted to kill me , eh ? You son of a bitch .
You wanted to kill me ?
You shit snake !
You always were !
Call an ambulance .
Let 's tie him up first .
Chema ? Why ?
Why ?
The ... garage .
The garage ...
Out of the way .
I 'm going to kill you .
Say hello .
She was furious this afternoon .
I had to kill her .
She never understood anything .
In fact , I thought you were cleverer
but you 've gone too far ...
Let me tell you what we 're going to do .
Hello ! Testing , testing .
Look at the camera .
First , I 'm going to beat you
for a while ...
until you lose consciousness .
I 'll wait till you come round , then cut your arms and legs .
Then I 'll cut you up .
Exactly how , I 'll see as I go along .
If I cut off a hand ,
I might put it on your head
like a coronet .
Those poofy things are great .
Or I might make you eat your ear . If I make a good job of it ,
I can take out your intestines without killing you .
Frightening , isn 't it ?
Look at me .
Frightening .
You 'll bleed heavily .
When you 're almost dead , I 'll shoot you in the mouth ...
then cut you up and get rid of you .
By the way , you did an appalling job on Castro .
Alright , then ...
we 're ready .
Don 't move .
Don 't move !
That hand !
I won 't harm you .
Tell me one thing .
The color of my eyes ?
JUSTICE AND THE LAW
Good afternoon .
When love , torture , death and money merge ,
events such as the one which has been in the news
these days take place .
The " Snuff Girls " case , as it 's been called .
Bosco was a sensitive and studious young man ,
a very normal person , according to his friends and family .
In this garden ...
he hid the bodies of 6 girls , missing since 1993 .
One of them was his girlfriend .
In this week the police have found many snuff movies
and papers which incriminate Jorge Castro
Professor of Cinema ,
who , the police say died accidentally on the 3rd ,
as he was about to start a snuff recording .
The police have given no further information about this .
This case marks the beginning in our country
of the " snuff movie " phenomenon .
Hi .
I couldn 't come before . The police have been hounding me .
Me too .
I saw you on TV .
By the way ...
I 'm going to switch it off .
This is the best part .
They do as I say .
How are you ?
I 'm coming out tomorrow .
I 've brought you something .
THE PRINCESS AND THE DWARF
I 've already got this edition .
This one 's dedicated .
I haven 't got my glasses .
The day I discovered the tunnels
I found the cameras ,
and I took one .
Why ?
You know me . I 'm a bastard .
You can punch me if you want .
I don 't want to .
Why don 't you look at me ?
I 'm going then .
Why ?
Because .
Okay then .
Good luck with your thesis .
I 've abandoned it .
Can we watch TV now ?
Granddad ...
read me this dedication please .
" First edition
February , 1992 ... "
Just the dedication .
" Poetry and prose collection " ,
Fancy a coffee ?
" No part of this work
can be reproduced in any form ... "
A spine-chilling case ,
a story of blood and terror
in which reality and fiction combine to produce something
of which no rational mind is capable .
We can only ask :
How can someone do something like that ?
Is there really a public that demands and consumes
this type of cinema ?
Well , the long awaited moment has arrived .
As announced , we have managed to get our hands
on one of those macabre tapes .
The images you 're about to see
are of Vanessa being savagely tortured ,
and subjected to all types of atrocities before being killed .
Unpleasant as it is to show these images ,
we think they are of interest to all .
The crude violence speaks for itself .
Here now are those images .
THE IMAGES YOU ARE ABOUT TO SEE
ARE EXTREMELY CRUDE AND VIOLENT .
Subtitulado por J.R. Media Services Burbank , California